Huntington Estate Papers
Huntington Estate Papers
1955-1976
Huntington family
12 linear ft.
Papers from the estate of the Huntington family.
2540008
Biographical History
The Huntington family were businessmen, art collectors, and philanthropists in early 20th century New York. Collis P. Huntington was a railroad builder and financier; he and his wife Arabella Duval Huntington collected art and supported various charities. Their son, Archer Milton Huntington, was an American philanthropist and poet and together with his wife, noted sculptor Anna Hyatt Huntington, became an enthusiastic patron of the arts.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Huntington Estate Papers consist primarily of legal and financial papers relating to the businesses and estates of Collis P. Huntington and his wife Arabella, and their son Archer Milton Huntingon and his wife Anna Vaughn Hyatt Huntington. The material includes bank statements, bills, correspondence, litigation documents, receipts, taxes, trust documents, wills, and similar material.
The collection has not been processed and the inventory below is a simple box list.
Related Material
See also the following:
Anna Hyatt Huntington Papers
Arabella Huntington Papers
Archer Milton Huntington Papers
Collis P. Huntington Papers
Subject and Genre Headings
Huntington, Anna Hyatt, 1876-1973.; Huntington, Arabella Duval, 1850 or 51-1924.; Huntington, Archer M. (Archer Milton), 1870-1955.; Huntington, Collis Potter, 1821-1900.; Huntington family.; Brookgreen Gardens.; Art -- Collectors and collecting -- United States.; Philanthropists -- United States.; Upper class -- United States.; Bank statements.; Correspondence.; Inventories.; Legal instruments.; Receipts (financial records); Tax returns.; Trust receipts.; Wills.; Collectors.; Philanthropists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Huntington estate papers
  - Financial - legal (Box 1)
  - Income tax, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Income tax return, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Conn. cap. gains + div. tax, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Capital gains tax conn., 1969 (Box 1)
  - Income tax return, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Bills and receipts, 1969 (Box 1)
  - American tel + tel easement (Box 1)
  - Park and forest matters (Box 1)
  - Corres, re gift tax returns (Box 1)
  - Gift tax returns, 1955-1956; 1963,; 1965-1966,; 1969-1973; 9 folders (Box 1)
  - Work Horse and Sancho Panza statues (Box 1)
  - Power of attorney (Box 1)
  - Suspense file (Box 1)
  - Deed American Geographical Society (Box 1)
  - Custodian acct. from, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Annuities, general papers (Box 1)
  - Trusts, general papers (Box 1)
  - U.S. Trust Co. cash statements from, 1967 (Box 1)
  - U.S. Trust Co. corres., 1967 (Box 1)
  - U.S. Trust Co. thru 1966 (Box 1)
  - U.S. Trust Co. (Box 1)
  - Bank of NY cash statements, 1966; 1967; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Hanover Trust Co. cash statements, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Hanover Tr. Co. general trust papers (Box 2)
  - Hanover Tr. Co. security statements, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Hanover Tr. thru 1966 (Box 2)
  - Sculpture Trust (Box 2)
  - Huntington financial/legal, restricted (Box 2)
  - Huntington, Anna Hyatt notes, drafts, worksheets, office memos (Box 2)
  - Ryle, Adelina and Edward F. (Box 2)
  - Anna Hyatt Huntington, re: bequests to natl. sculpt society + natl. acad. of design (Box 2)
  - Robert Carluzzi purchase (Box 2)
  - Federal income tax, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Income tax, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Fed. income tax, 1972; 1973; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Brookgreen Gardens (Box 2)
  - Matter of Edward D. and Susan M. Rose (Box 2)
  - Farm operations matters (Box 3)
  - Account - State Planters Bank (Box 3)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Co., genl. corres. all trusts and investment programs; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Anna Hyatt Huntington - Morgan - Guaranty Trust - Trust No. 1, Dec. 1955 (Box 3)
  - Anna H. Huntington Park (Box 3)
  - Real Estate, conveyance to rilling (Box 3)
  - Estate of Archer M. Huntington
    - Exhibit B, third group copies of trust investments (Box 4)
    - Exhibit B2, First and second groups list of items comprising corpora of trusts and Exhibit D copies of annuity contracts (Box 4)
    - Form E-3 Exhibit A, Ante Mortem gifts explanatory Exhibits A, B, C & D (Box 4)
    - Index to files and legal memos (3 copies) (Box 4)
    - Sunset Hill Road, Redding, Connecticut parcel "A" (Box 4)
    - Last will and testament of Archer Milton Huntington, 33 copies (Box 4)
    - A.M Huntington 2357, A/8 executor's accounting (Box 4)
    - A-4 inventory (Box 4)
    - A-7 paid bills for admin. expenses (Box 4)
    - A-5 copies of AMH will (Box 4)
    - Redding probate court (Box 4)
    - Estate of Archer M. Huntington, Jan 1963; correspondence (Box 4)
    - Exhibit B, Third group copies of trust instruments (Box 5)
    - 2357/B corres., 1/1/62 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence file, 1/1/60 - 12/28/61 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence file 2357, 1955-1961; 5 folders (Box 5)
  - Loose papers of the Connecticut Bank and Trust co. and Anna Hyatt Huntington Trustees, Archer M. Huntington Trust (Box 5)
  - Anna Hyatt Huntington Trust in Account with Hartford National Bank and Trust Co. (Box 5)
  - City Natl. Bank (Box 5)
  - The Bridgeport City Trust Co. (Box 5)
  - City National Bank (Box 5)
  - JP Morgan Copies - Archer C Huntington 2357 - C, 1955-1957; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Misc. Information on Trusts 2357 D (Box 6)
  - Will of Collis P. Huntington (also) will of Henry P. Huntington, 3/13/97 (Box 6)
  - Archer M. Huntington Trust by Arabella H. 2357 D - 2, 1997-1999; 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Huntington, Archer 2357 D, 23 folders (Box 6)
    2357 D 9, 9A, 9B
    2357 D 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19
    2357 D 20, 21, 22, 23, 24, 25, 26, 27, 28, 29
  - Huntington, Archer 2357 D, cont., 29 folders (Box 7)
    2357 D 30, 31, 32, 33, 34, 35, 36, 37, 38, 39
    2357 D 40, 41, 42, 43, 44, 45, 46, 47, 48, 49A, 49B, 49C, 49D
    2357 D 50, 51A, 52, 53, 54, 55
  - Bank of New York litigation (Box 7)
  - Conveyance to charities (Box 7)
  - 2357 L-3 Preparation of return (Box 8)
  - 2357 L-4 Copies of JPM letters, life-time gifts (Box 8)
  - 2357 L-5 Supporting documents, extra copies (Box 8)
  - 2357 L-6 Audit conference notes (Box 8)
  - 2357 L-7 Audit memos and copies of correspondence (Box 8)
  - 2357 L-8 Recomputations following audit (Box 8)
  - 2357 L-9 Claim for refund (Box 8)
  - 2357 L-10 Federal income gift taxes (Box 8)
  - 2357 L- 11 Conn. taxes (Box 8)
  - Forms 1041 #2357 L/15 Fiduciary income tax return (Box 8)
  - 2357 L/16 Allocation (Box 8)
  - Estate of Archer M. Huntington allocation of refund 2357-L-17 (Box 8)
  - 2357 M1 - Legal memos - will construction generally (Box 9)
  - 2357 M2 - Legal memos - apportionment, proration and contribution (Box 9)
  - 2357 M3 - Legal memos - probate procedure generally (Box 9)
  - 2357 M5 - Legal memos - investment powers (Box 9)
  - 2357 M6 - New York Estate Tax and Real Estate (Box 9)
  - 2357 M7 - Legal memos - Arabella D. Huntington Trusts (Box 9)
  - 2357 M8 - Legal memos - Collis P. Huntington Will interpretation (Box 9)
  - 2357 N Billing records and information (Box 9)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Co. of NY PE 600 Tabulation of Securities, 8/58 - 1/63 (Box 9)
  - Estate of Archer M. Huntington P-00600, 12/21/60 - 12/15/64 (Box 9)
  - Archer M. Huntington PE006000 Current, 1963 (Box 9)
  - PE858, 4 folders (Box 9)
  - Archer M. Huntington 2357 0-1 PE00600 correspondence (Box 10)
  - Estate of Archer M. Huntington PE 600
    - U-1 N.Y. Litigation Estate of Collis P. Huntington, 12/55 - 10/59 (Box 10)
  - Estate of Arabella D. Huntington 2357 P
    - Arabella Est. Taxes N.Y. + Cal. 2357 (4) (Box 10)
    - Arabella Accounting 2357 (5) (Box 10)
    - File Ancillary Administration and Fed. Est. Tax 2357 (6) P (Box 10)
  - Arabella Huntington Trust Inter - Vivos Trust 2357 V4, 1897-1899 (Box 10)
  - Arabella Huntington Trust Inter - Vivos 2357 V-3 + V-4 (Box 10)
  - 2357 U - 2 N.Y. Litigation estate of Arabella D. Huntington (Box 10)
  - 2357/1 Correspondence litigation +63, 1/2/62 (Box 11)
  - 2357 Z/6 Connecticut Practice (Box 11)
  - Est. Archer M. Huntington 2357 - V Redondo stock sale, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Estate of Archer M. Huntington (Box 11)
  - Sources of information (Box 11)
  - Memoranda to counsel (Box 11)
  - Davis and Cheney Docket (Box 11)
  - Satisfaction of orders of executor's accounts (Box 11)
  - Satisfaction of orders of proration (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, March 16, 1974 (Box 11)
  - Estate of Anna H. Huntington (Box 11)
  - Anna H. Huntington correspondence, 1976 (Box 11)
  - Est. Anna H. Huntington
    - 4717 B correspondence, 1975 (Box 11)
    - 4717 BB Copies of Bank of N.Y. correspondence (Box 12)
    - 4717 F work in progress (Box 12)
    - Fee information (Box 12)
    - 4717 Federal estate tax (Box 12)
    - 4717 I#2 Federal estate audit (Box 12)
    - 4717 I#2 J notes and memos (Box 12)
    - 4717J Conn. succession tax (Box 12)
    - 4717 final account (Box 12)
    - Bank of New York (Duplicate) financial statements #4717- L (Box 12)
    - 4717 D extra copies (Box 12)
    - 2358L will file correspondence (Box 12)
    - 4717C Personal income tax (empty file) (Box 12)
    - 4717H Estate income tax (Box 12)
    - 4717E Inventory (Box 12)
    - 4717Q Judicial proceeds for settlement Archer M. Huntington (Box 12)
  - Bank of New York as Trustee of eight trusts established by Archer M. Huntington (Box 12)